Hello everyone, let's take a look at some of the problems that need to be avoided in the process of recording animation in software.
Here we import an OBJ to do morph target.
After opening it in the right position, we select open at the bottom.
Select morph target for the target type.
The morph target is the number of times we have overacted.
The smaller the number, the less the number of times we have overacted.
The faster we overact, the faster we overact.
So when we set the morph target, try to set it a little higher.
This can prevent some cross-interference problems caused by overacting too fast.
Also, in the process of morph target, if the movement is too different,
such as turning around, or some other problems,
it is best to turn your model in the software first,
then do the morph target.
Don't make too much of a difference.
Next, we can see that after we have finished the movement,
the model's right hand is more stable.
But if we turn to the left hand of the model,
we will find that it is a little unstable.
The reason why it is unstable is because of the cross-interference between the model's hand and chest.
When there is a cross-interference in the model,
there is also a cross-interference in the model's outer panel,
because the distance between them is very close.
The fabric itself is relatively thin, and the tight position may be fine,
but in places where there are more fabric piled up,
its instability will be more obvious,
because there are already a lot of grid here.
Plus, their collision distance now becomes very close,
and it is easy to cause instability.
In such a situation,
it may be easier to solve some more tight panels.
You can fix it directly through the fixing needle,
fix it on the virtual model,
and force it to be fixed in that position.
But if there is a lot of fabric,
there is no way to use the function of fixing it to the virtual model.
In general, we recommend that you try not to let the movement have some cross-interference.
Because once there is a cross-interference,
you separate the movement from the fabric itself.
It also has a calculation here.
So before the official recording starts,
make sure your model is in the process of animation recording.
Otherwise, there may be a cross-interference in the process of animation recording.
Next, let's look at the second case.
In this case,
we will see that after opening the animation editor,
when dragging the progress bar at the bottom,
this model will pass to the ground.
In our software,
there will be conflicts on the ground under default conditions.
It is to prevent the panel from falling to the ground below.
In this case,
if we continue to maintain the conflicts on the ground,
then the panel will definitely be forced above the ground.
Therefore, the clothing looks like there is a breakdown.
Then we need to set up the conflicts on the ground.
In the background of the 3D space,
right-click and select the model attribute.
Open the ground in the attribute editor.
The ground is randomly selected conflicts.
When you select a conflict,
we can set its overall ground height to negative.
Then we have the position of the conflict below the ground.
Then you can do a test in advance.
Use a piece of board to simulate
and see its final height.
Next, let's look at another case.
In this case,
I have done some details of the clothes in advance.
Including I used the name line.
But here you can see that
the name line I used is all sticked.
First, we can switch to the top stitch,
which is the window of the name line.
Click the title name here,
the bottom window, and switch to top stitch.
Then when we select a top stitch,
which is the type of the name line,
in the attribute editor,
there is a name line of this type.
Its attribute settings.
Here we will see that there is a type at the bottom.
There are two options for the type.
One is obj and the other is texture.
When we change the type to obj,
we can see that the details of the name line here
will be richer.
But this will lead to certain problems.
When we make a mirror,
the problem may occur.
Because the number of its grid is large,
it is just a little more.
But when you export the LAMBEC file,
these name line grids will be animated
along with the version.
Then after they have an animation,
the whole project file will become very large.
There may be some problems when exporting.
So please,
in the process of making some animations,
convert these name lines into texture.
Next, let's take a look at
the process of recording the animation.
Sometimes we may need to
make some changes to the costume.
In the process of making some changes,
you need to avoid some problems.
Sometimes, when we started recording the animation,
we didn't find any problems.
After we recorded the animation to a certain number of frames,
we found that there were some differences
or unstable places in the version.
Some friends may change it
under this number of frames.
You will find that if you add some
false frames or edit the version,
the animation recorded before
will be gone.
This is because our animation
is moving along the grid.
So in the process of recording the animation
to a certain number of frames,
if you change the costume,
due to the lack of the costume animation,
when we drag the progress bar
back to the first frame,
the previous action and clothes
will not match.
First, if you accidentally encounter
such a problem,
please pause the simulation
and then save the current action
of this OBJ model.
After the first frame,
you can start to edit your costume.
This means that we need to
start recording the animation again from the beginning.
In addition to the false frame
that will cause the animation recorded before to fail,
if you change the grid peak
and do some other operations,
there may be such an animation loss problem.
So in the process of recording the animation,
you must remember to go back to the initial frame
and continue to edit.
Next, let's take a look at
what common operations
can be done.
First of all, these functions
will usually cause the grid to reset,
including, but not least,
modifying the board,
modifying the line,
adjusting the particle diameter,
and increasing the false frame
and adjusting the rendering thickness.
Note that this is to adjust the rendering thickness
rather than the collision thickness,
because the collision thickness
is actually just the air wall setting,
but the rendering thickness
can be adjusted.
The next question
is about our layer settings.
First of all, before you record the animation,
you may use some layers,
such as adding a multiple layer to the top layer,
so that it can be received in the skirt.
These settings can be maintained
in a static state,
but there may be some problems
under the dynamic model.
You can see here
that in the process of
modifying to half,
there are already some conflict problems.
In this process,
you can see that
there are some problems
in our sleeves or belt.
This is because when the animation
is simulated to this action,
the sleeves and skirt collide,
and they begin to identify layers.
It's like this,
it won't touch each other in the early stages of the version,
but if there are some collisions
when it is simulated to the middle stage,
we can cancel the layer before it collides.
The layer tool
is that once you simulate stability,
there is no problem,
so we can pull the progress bar back a little
and set the layer to zero,
and then continue to record the animation.
Because the layer will not affect the grid arrangement,
so if we start recording the animation,
the animation will not disappear.
Here I have already recorded a section,
now let's show this section
to see if the layer is not applied,
what will happen if we start recording?
Here we can see
that if we do not set the layer,
it may be more stable.
So usually,
whether it is recording an animation
or doing a static model,
we can check
if the layer is set
to cause such a problem.
Of course, sometimes,
it doesn't matter if you use the layer,
it depends on whether
the second time and other versions
have collisions.
Then let's look at some settings
about the animation part.
First of all,
we can see that this animation bar
is only set to three,
but they will merge into a complete animation.
Then the parts that are covered
and recorded will not be retained,
it will only retain the part
that we replaced later.
Here we show you
that here we have just
modified the layer,
so we recorded a section
and covered the previous section.
After that,
we can see that
this animation bar
is set to a stable,
no layers section.
Even if we hide
these action bars
in the software,
as long as these animations are still there
and not deleted,
it will still be covered.
Of course,
the part that the animation
will be covered
is only the part
that is blocked by it.
If you don't want to keep
those animations recorded later,
you can delete them with the right-click.
In addition,
when some clothes are hidden
when they are leaked,
for example,
here I choose the skirt
and press Shift-Q to hide them.
At this time,
if I choose to leak the Olympic file,
the skirt part will not be leaked.
Here we can see that
only the animation above
has been leaked.
That's all about the animation.
Thank you for watching.